

# **Marcin Urbański**

## Software Engineer









I am full-stack software developer with 1.5 year of commercial experience. Currently I would like to develop myself in functional paradigm (i.e. Scala), but working in Android, Java EE, Javascript is interesting for me as well. I like solving problems and giving another point of view to discussion. I am able to quickly adapt new technologies. Responsive, reactive, creative, positive...

Well experienced in working as a part of a team and focusing on achieving collective goals. Skilled in tackling problems in a logical manner. Constantly searching for the opportunity to face new challenges and gain further experience.

**=** +47 406 274 10

**--** +48 506 196 394

Contact me

## **Experience**

## Sør-Trøndelag University College in Trondheim, Norway

Intern as Software Developer • Aug, 2015 – Feb, 2016

Preparing UML diagrams and coding in Java and ActionScript/Flex. My work involves developing library that generates Excel and Word documents (with charts and drawings), creating animated charts, refactoring settings in application (to be more elastic), developing component, which displays text as interactive word cloud.

Being here was for me good lesson to experience Norwegian way of working. I learned a lots useful tips regarding UX and UI. Working in ActionScript helped me to understand better other languages (especially things that missing in AS3 and present in Java) and with it I have unique experience on job market.

### Javeo

#### Junior Software Developer • May, 2015 – Aug, 2015

I was responsible for adapting law changes to Spring Web Application owned by insurance company. That job include writing DB procedures, changing JSP pages and testing.

I worked on three Android App. Two of them were for public transportation (bus ticket using NFC) and third one was implementation of my boss great idea - app for music enthusiasts - Neutralizer, which matches equalizer settings to personal hearing.

### **Samsung R&D Poland**

### Junior Software Engineer • Oct, 2014 - May, 2015

During work in Samsung I learned how to be professional. In my team we were using Scrum for developing internal corporate systems to automate employees work.

One of the project was about integrating Jira with PLM (Korean Project Management System). My work involved creating Angular application to display issues from PLM in Jira, writing tests in Groovy, helping to develop micro-services that synchronize both systems, developing a plugin that automatically configures Jira instance to be able to work with our system (i.e. setting up special issue types).

I created some prototype applications using Node.Js and Scala in Play framework (for next generation of Jira plugins). While working in Samsung I participated in many workshops regarding TDD and BDD.

### Intern • Jun, 2014 - Sep, 2014

I was responsible for developing <u>Jira</u>, <u>Confluence and Bamboo plugins</u> to automate work in that systems. I created plugin to display assignees activity on specific charts, created weekly reports generator, solved some bugs in KPI calculator (report plugin in Jira) and I created plugin for storing personal Notes on Jira's dashboard (using Markdown). Mostly I was using Java (including Java EE) and Javascript.

I also created prototype of Android app - called Smartmouse, which changed smartphone into computer mouse. During intern I fell in love with Agile.

### **Copernicus Science Center in Warsaw**

Science Communicator • Apr, 2011 – Dec, 2012

Working here helped me to develop *soft skills*, which are in my opinion as important as technical one (in software development field). Working in team, explaining *difficult terms* in *simple words*, being responsible for others are only ones of many skills that I improved there.

In details my work was about showing experiments mainly in a field of optics, human anatomy, anthropology and zoology to wide range of visitors, mostly children and teenagers and explaining the basic optical phenomenon of interference, diffraction, polarization to groups of school students.

## **Programming skills**

 $\star\star\star\star$   $\star$  Java

**★★★☆☆ Android** 

 $\star\star \star \Leftrightarrow \Leftrightarrow \Leftrightarrow$  Scala

**★★★★** ActionScript/Flex

 $\star\star\star\star$   $\Leftrightarrow$  Javascript

 $\star\star \star \Leftrightarrow \Leftrightarrow$  Python

 $\star \star \Leftrightarrow \Leftrightarrow \Leftrightarrow$  Kotlin

## **Personal skills**

#### Communication

Developed a wide range of communication skills needed to maintain contact with visitors and explain them scientific concepts while working in Copernicus Science Center as Science Communicator

#### **Team Work**

Worked as a part of a team in the gallery exhibition while volunteering at Copernicus Science Center, sharing tasks and responsibilities with other team members in order to achieve the team goals

### Time-Management

Being a student I successfully managed time connecting studies with working.

### Leadership & Responsibility

Responsible for the coordination of the work of subordinates while being elected as a shift-manager in Copernicus Science Center

### **Problem Solving & Critical Thinking**

Acquired planning and budgeting skills while traveling around East Asia, faced a number of problems that occurred on a way, learned how to handle difficult and unexpected situations

## **Education**

### **Warsaw University of Technology**

Faculty of Electronics and Information Technology

Engineer Degree, Computer Science • Oct, 2011 – Feb, 2015

The BEST Polish Technical University (ranking)

- GPA 4.26/5.00
- Engineer Thesis -5.00/5.00
- Engineer Thesis defence 5.00/5.00

Engineer thesis: *Steganography in mobile devices and its detection* Led by: D.Sc. Wojciech Mazurczyk

I implemented solution, which proves that <u>Android Permission System</u> may lead to privacy leaks or deceive **Two Factor Authentication** 

I invented four new Covert Channels (which may lead to privacy leaks in Android). I also prepared three algorithms, which could help to detect steganography in Android using device's statistics.

I was a part of international team, which was involved in research and development of steganography. **Here** you can find our papers.

### Jan Kochanowski's VI L.O. in Radom

Highschool • Main subject: Math, Physics and Computer Science Sep, 2007 – Oct, 2010

I passed my final exam with great grades:

• Extended Math – 96%

- Base Math 98%
- Extended Physics 83%

### **Courses**

### **Programming Mobile Applications for Android Systems: Part 1**

Grade Achieved: 98.2% • University of Maryland, College Park on Coursera Certificate earned on September 30, 2015

### **Programming Mobile Applications for Android Systems: Part 2**

Grade Achieved: 99.2% • University of Maryland, College Park on Coursera Certificate earned on September 30, 2015

### **Programming Mobile Applications for Android Systems: Concurrency**

Grade Achieved: 99.8% • Vanderbilt University on Coursera Certificate earned on November 16, 2015

## My own projects

### **Idealstorm**

### Meteor framework • Heroku • PaperJs

Project-prototype to display your ideas as animated objects on website

### **Daily selfie**

#### Android • Roboticum • GreenBot EventBus

Now you will never forget to take you daily selfie :-)

## Recognition

#### 1. Steganography detection in mobile devices

Seeing the Unseen: Revealing Mobile Malware Hidden Communications via Energy Consumption and Artificial Intelligence

L. Caviglione, M. Gaggero, J-F. Lalande, M. Urbanski, W. Mazurczyk • 2015

### 2. Steganography detection in mobile devices

Move Together and You are Dead: Detecting Local Covert Channels Using Process Activity Correlation on Android Smartphones

M. Urbanski, W. Mazurczyk, J-F. Lalande, L. Caviglione • 2015

## **Associations**

## Ikar • Sailing Club • Jedlnia-Letnisko

Member • 2015 – Present

Sailing duties and training.

# How do I spend my free time?

- ♥ Sailing
- Getting lost in unknown places
- Drawing
- Steganography
- Literature of absurd fiction
- Eating potatoes